[MUSIC]
موسيقى     ترجمه: د/ أحمد شحاته
Hi, Prof Navarro here >> And I'm Alex LaBon.
مرحبا، هنا البروفيسور نافارو وأنا أليكس لابون.
>> Okay, Alex.
حسناً أليكس.
What will we be covering in today's lecture?
ما الذي سنغطيه في محاضرة اليوم؟
>> Well today we'll be talking credit cards and debit cards.
حسناً اليوم سنتحدث عن بطاقات الإئتمان و بطاقات الصراف الآلي.
We'll go into the differences between the two and
سنتحدث عن الفرق بين البطاقتين و
talk about what this beast called APR actually is.
سنتحدث حول حقيقة الوحش المدعو آي آر بي ( معدل الفائدة السنوية المئوية).
And we'll also talk about how to best use these two types of cards to better
كما سنتحدث عن الطريقة الأفضل لاستخدام هذين النوعين من البطاقات حتى
manage your money.
تدير أموالك بشكل أفضل.
>> All right man, so what's the bigger picture here with these things?
حسناً يا رجل، ماهي الصورة الأكبر في هذه الأمور؟
>> Well, a lot of younger folks, like me, are hesitant to take on debt.
أيضا، الكثير من الناس الأصغر سنا، مثلى، ومترددة في اخذ الدين.
Why should we willingly put ourselves at the behest of huge banks?
لماذا ينبغي لنا أن نضع أنفسنا متطوعين تحت وصاية المصارف الكبيرة؟
>> Going off the grid, are we?
للهروب من المصيدة ، صحيح؟
>> [LAUGH] Not quite, but credit cards can be dangerous.
[يضحك] ليس تماما، لكن بطاقات الائتمان يمكن أن تكون خطيرة.
They encourage you to spend less reasonably sometimes and
هي تشجعك على أن تنفق بشكل أقل واقعية وفي بعض الأحيان
by their nature encourage debt to the man.
بطبيعتها تشجع على أخذ الدين.
>> So, two thumbs down on credit cards?
إذاً،بطاقات الائتمان سيئة؟
>> Not exactly.
ليس تماماً.
If you manage them intelligently,
إذا أدرتهم بذكاء.
you can reap the benefits of credit card without being neck deep in debt.
يمكنك جني فوائد بطاقة الائتمان من دون أن تغرق في الديون
It's all about having a plan in mind for handling our money the best we can.
كله متعلق فقط بوجود خطة لدينا للتعامل الأمثل مع أموالنا بقدر المستطاع
>> Okay, so what are the main takeaways from this lesson?
حسناً، إذا ما هي برأيك الفائدة الرئيسية التي تؤخذ من هذا الدرس؟
>> Well, I'll show you why a debit card excels for small, everyday expenses,
حسناً، سأريك لماذا تتفوق بطاقات السحب الآلي في المصروفات اليومية الصغيرة
while a credit card is useful sometimes for unexpected costs or purchasing
بينما بطاقة الائتمان مفيدة للنكاليف الغير متوقعة أو شراء سلعة
expensive but useful capital goods >> So each card has its strength and
غالية لكنها مفيدة كالسلع الاستثمارية حيث لك بطاقة نقاط قوة و
weaknesses, is that what you're saying?
ضعف، هل هذا ما تقوله؟
>> Yup, and it'll help our students develop an idea of how you use these two
نعم، ستساعد طلابنا في تطوير فكرة عن كيفية استخدام الإثنتين
together in harmony.
معاً في تناغم.
>> All right sounds like a plan.
جيد، انها تبدو لي كخطة.
Where do you want to start today?
إين تريد أن تبدأ اليوم؟
>> We'll start with debit cards.
سنبدأ مع بطاقات الصراف الآلي.
>> All righty.
حسناً
Now off you go.
الآن فلتبدأ.
[MUSIC]
موسيقى     ترجمه: د/ أحمد شحاته